A Guide to the Thomas Overton Moss papers, 1917-1928
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Thomas Overton Moss papers, 1917-1928
The Library of Virginia
53817
.175 cubic feet (1 box)
Thomas Overton Moss
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased
Biographical Information
Thomas Overton Moss was born 13 October 1893 in Hanover County, Virginia, to Thomas Overton Moss (b. 1839) and Nina Wood Moss (1857-1930). He attended Hampden-Sydney College and received his law degree from T.C. Williams School of Law at the University of Richmond. Moss moved to Richmond, Virginia, where he began practicing law. He also became active in local and state politics. Moss married Virginia Johnson in 1919 and they divorced ca. 1931. His second wife was named Louise. Moss married a third time on 9 August 1937 to Doris Braur Mann (1905-1988) of Washington D.C., and they had an adopted daughter. Moss died 23 June 1939 in Richmond, and was buried in Hollywood Cemetery.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1917-1918, of Thomas Overton Moss (1893-1939) of Richmond, Virginia, consisting of letters of recommendation, 1917-1918, for Moss as an officer in the United States Navy Reserve and to be assistant paymaster aboard the USS Middlesex; correspondence with Harry F. Byrd (1887-1966) regarding politics and Byrd's governorship; correspondence, 1925-1928, regarding Moss's service in the Officer Reserve Corps and state and local politics; and related papers.
Contents List
- Letters of recommendation for position in Naval Reserve, December 1917 (Folder 1)
- Letters of recommendation for position of assistant paymaster on the USS Middlesex, 1 May 1918 (Folder 2)
- Letters of recommendation, 14 May 1918 (Folder 3)
- Correspondence: Harry F. Byrd, 1925 (Folder 4)
- Correspondence: Harry F. Byrd, 1926 (Folder 5)
- Correspondence: Harry F. Byrd, 1927-1928 (Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1925 (Folder 7)
- Correspondence, January-February 1926 (Folder 8)
- Correspondence, March-December 1926 (Folder 9)
- Correspondence, January 1927 (Folder 10)
- Correspondence, February-April 1927 (Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1928 (Folder 12)
- Commonwealth of Virginia Adjutant General's Office--special orders, staff orders, and memoranda, 1926-1928 (Folder 13)
- Officers' Reserve Corps papers--regulations, orders, applications, and examinations, 1924-1926 (Folder 14)
- City (Richmond) Democratic Committee, 1926-1927 (Folder 15)
- Schedule of ceremonies, ball committee, State Fair, 5 October 1928 (Folder 16)